Hey everyone!
Iin this video we're
going to set up
a Adobe Stock and
Adobe Experience
Manager Assets integration.
Introducing AM 6.4.2.
Note that this integration
requires an Enterprise
Adobe Stock file
AM 6.4 with service pack
2 installed.
To perform some of
these operations
You might need a Adobe
admin permissions on
on AEM Adobe IO console. And
access to your admin console.
I'm using AMC 6.4 GA
version.
Let's get started.
From your main
home homepage .
Click on Tools >Deployment
and Select Packages.
Let's upload and install
the AEM 6.
service pack .
You can find the
downloadable link for
the service pack along
with this video.
Browse to find the service
pack and install it.
Note that it might
take a few seconds
for the installation
to complete . As
an additional step
you're required to
reinstall the
Adobe Stock Package .
At this point
we have taken care of all the
prerequisites for this integration .
Let's navigate back to AEM
homepage and click
Tools> Security
and select Adobe IMS
configuration.
Nearly all Adobe services
require your
application
to authenticate through
the Adobe Identity Management
System to receive Client credentials.
The client credentials determine
the access and permissions
granted to your application .
Any API that accesses a
a service or content on
behalf of an end user
authenticates using O oath
and J Sand
Webtop and standards.
Let's create a new
Adobe IMS configuration
For cloud solutions
Let's Select Adobe Stock
and then create a new certificate .
Provide a name for your certificate
and then click Create.
To retrieve the access token -we
should add the certificates
public key to the
technical account on Adobe IO.
We will be covering
this in our next step .
Click Ok and download the
public key to your drive .
Open a new tab and navigate
to Adobe IO console
Make sure to select your
organization and you should
be able to see a list of
existing integrations .
Let's create a new integration
to access Adobe Stock API
and click continue. Under
Creative Cloud Solutions
you should be able to see
Adobe Stock Service Account
integration -if the entitlement
is added to your organization
If the application makes
API requisits to a service
on behalf of itself or an
enterprise organization
you will need to configure
a service account integration
Service accounts are
similar to user accounts but,
they are unique to your application
and have additional security requirements.
You can also check out the
documentation for
Adobe Stock API
here.
Select the service account
integration option
and then click Continue .
Provide a name and description
for your integration.
For public keys
certificate-
let's browse and
upload the public key we saved
to our drive from AEM.  For
Adobe Stock configuation
you can either use the default
Adobe Stock configuaration
or create a new configuration
within Adobe admin console.
And it should show up under
the license dropdown
For this particular account
we have two additional
profiles created.
Let's open our admin
console in a new tab
and under Products and
Adobe Stock
you should be
able to view the user admins
and permissions
for your Adobe Stock profile
Under Permissions you have an
option to add references that
need to be provided everytime
you try to license an asset.
These references can be
optional or mandatory.
Let's open the mandatory
references and you can notice
that project name and cross
sender references are added as mandatory.
Let's also check out
optional references
used for this configuration.
We have kept the
country reference as optional .
Let's navigate back
to our integration window
and select the Adobe Stock
configuration and
create integration
Upon successful integration
you can click to view the
integration details
From the JWTT tab copy the
payload details.
Switch
back to an Adobe IMS window.
And then click next.
Paste the JWT payload
in the payload field.
Select and copy the
IMS authorization server URL
from the payload
Provide a title for your IMS
technical account
configuration then
paste the authorization server URL.
Switch back to the Adobe IO console
and copy the client secret
and API key details
and paste the values into the
corresponding fields in your
IMS configuration window.
Click Create to complete
the configuration.
Select the configuration and
perform the health check
to make sure you receive the top
configuration for
your IMS integration .
Now, we need to set up
cloud services for
Adobe Stock AEM integration.
From your AEM home page
Click on Tools> Cloud
Services and then click
on Adobe Stock. Click
on the create option to
create a new stock
configuration
Provide a title
and select the adobe IMS
configuration we created in
the previous step . Make sure
to select the
environment as production
Stage environment option
won't be removed in
the next AEM release update and
it is recommended by Adobe
to use a production environment
For licensed asset path field
you can select the
/ content/ dam path
This field is part
of an upcoming release
and for 6.4.2
it is not relevant .
Select the locale as English
and save and close your cloud
configuration. At this point
we have successfully integrated
Adobe Stock with AEM assets.
Admin can
assign this cloud
configuration to certain users
or a group. Open to view the
properties of the stock
cloud configuration and
under user or group
let's add admins and dam users .
This means
users belonging to the
following group would be able
to license an asset from
our Adobe Stock and save it
to AME assets. Save youf
changes and exit the window .
Let's make sure that our integration
is successful by licensing
an asset from our Adobe
stock within AEM assets UI.
From you AME home page
click on Assets
and you can now see an
option to search Adobe stock
For a user who doesn't
belong to the group-
Probably shouldn't
use the Adobe stock
cloud service. The
option would be hidden.
Click on search Adobe Stock
option and search for stock
images with the key word
Christmas. Select an asset
and click on license and
try to save it . You should now
be able to see a window with
the mandatory references
and optional references
we added
to our stock
configuration.
Provide the detais for your
project name, cost,
sender and locale.
Click to the license option
and you have now
successfully licensed
an asset from Adobe Stock
and we can save the
asset to AEM assets .