Translator: Do you speak Hindi.
Lady: Yes a little bit.
English
Translator: When these people were away,
a lady had come here?
Lady: Yes.
Translator: Where is she now? What happened to her.
Lady: The one who had come here a
few days ago?
Translator: The one who was sick,
when these people had met you earlier.
I know nothing about her.
Translator: The one who had come earlier
and was sent to hospital later.
Lady: She was sent to Mathura hospital
They came back, and didn't tell us anything more.
What do we know?
Translator: What happened to her?
She made one guard sick. Because of her we
got sick.
The one who was doing cleaning job
got ill.
Then Madam said that if one gets sick.
all will get sick.
Whoever will do the cleaning will become ill
Then she was admitted in Mathura.
After that happened we don't know.
English.
Translator: What is your name? Your age
and when did you come to Vrindavan.
What age were you widowed?
It is two year now I have come here
to Vrindavan.
I am now 65 years old.
Translator: How old?
Lady: 60 and 5 years, (65 years)
I came in 1983 to  Vrindavan.
My husband has expired now around 6 to 7 years.
He died around the age of 55 or 60.
What is your name?
Manju Haldar.
English